[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&gt；&gt；Douglas：这个模型的好处之一就是它完全改变了
&gt;&gt; Douglas: So one of the nice things about this model is it completely changes
黑客的经济学。
the economics of hacking.
在大多数架构中，如果你可以混淆一个对象，基本上，
In most architectures, if you can confuse an object, basically,
这样你就可以访问系统中的所有东西。
that gives you access to everything in the system.
而在这个模型中，
Whereas in this model,
如果你能混淆一个对象，你会得到该对象的能力，但是
if you can confuse an object, you get the capabilities of that object but
只有这样，在大多数情况下-&gt；&gt；扬声器2：那么一个令人困惑的对象是什么？
only that and in most cases- &gt;&gt; Speaker 2: So is a confusing objects?
道格拉斯：是的。对象未正确创建，并且
&gt;&gt; Douglas: Yeah. The object is not created correctly and
你可以让它做一些它不应该做的事情。
you can cause it to do something that it's not supposed to do.
&gt；&gt；扬声器2：好的。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Okay.
&gt；&gt；Douglas：您可能能够控制该对象可以做什么，但是
&gt;&gt; Douglas: You might be able to get control of what that object can do but
你不能控制系统所能做的一切。
you don't get control of everything that the system can do.
所以我们改变了黑客的经济学，
So we changed the economics of hacking,
YouTube上有一个关于这些东西的很好的演讲，
there's a really nice talk on YouTube about this stuff,
“懒惰程序员安全计算指南”(The Lazy Programmer‘s Guide to Secure Computing)，作者：Mark Stiegler。
The Lazy Programmer's Guide to Secure Computing by Mark Stiegler.
Stiegler的前提是最好的程序员是懒惰的，但是
Stiegler's premise is that the best programmers are lazy but
他们懒惰的方式避免了未来的工作。
they're lazy in a way which avoids future work.
如果你采用这种方法
And if you take that approach that
您也倾向于引导自己使用安全系统。
you tend to lead yourself to secure systems as well.
&gt；&gt；Douglas：今天早上我们在发现渗漏的地方做了这个练习
&gt;&gt; Douglas: So this morning we did this exercise where we've found this leakage
因为这所做的意想不到的事情危及了我们的安全。
because of the unexpected thing that this does which compromised our security.
所以我们需要了解这些东西，我们需要为它做计划，我们需要改进
So we need to understand for this stuff, we need to plan for it, we need to improve
语言，我们需要提高我们对语言的理解
the language, we need to improve our understanding of the language so
我们不会因此而妥协。
that we're not compromised by it.
这个攻击是混淆攻击的一个例子，这就是为什么我如此讨厌混淆
That attack is an example of a confusion attack, and that's why I hate confusion so
很大程度上是因为混乱是导致我们的系统失败的原因。
much because confusion is what causes our systems to fail.
混乱帮助敌人。
Confusion aids the enemy.
bug是混乱的表现，但安全漏洞也是表现
Bugs are a manifestation of confusion but also security exploits are manifestation
混乱的情况下，通常攻击者会接管
of confusion and usually attackers get to take over
当他们对我们的系统的理解比我们的更好时。
a systems when their understanding of our systems are better than ours.
不幸的是，这种情况经常发生，而我们阻止这种情况的方法
And unfortunately, that tends to happen a lot and the way we stop that
就是更好地了解我们自己的系统和
is by getting a better understanding of our own systems and
我们通过尽可能消除许多混淆的来源来做到这一点。
we do that by eliminating is many sources of confusion as possible.
我不能容忍混乱，我想尽可能地消除混乱。
I have no tolerance for confusion, I want to eliminate as much confusion as I can.
&gt；&gt；扬声器3：混淆攻击是指您不了解[INAUDIBLE]的工作原理。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Confusion attack is when you don't understand how [INAUDIBLE] it works.
&gt；&gt；Douglas：我们认为系统以一种特殊的方式工作，攻击者通过
&gt;&gt; Douglas: We think the system works in a particular way and the attacker by
研究这些数字发现这不是我们的工作方式，他能够利用这一点。
studying those figures out that's not how we work and he's able to exploit that.
事实上，几乎所有的安全漏洞都是这样的，
In fact, virtually all security exploits are like that,
我们从来没有故意公开然后投入生产的代码
that we never intentionally go public and then into production with code that
我们知道它有安全漏洞
we know has security vulnerabilities in it and yet
所部署的所有内容都存在安全漏洞，并且
everything that's ever been deployed has security vulnerabilities in it and
这是因为我们对自己的系统如何运作感到困惑。
it's because we're confused about how our own systems work.
我们不能再这样了。
We need to stop doing that.
因此，伴随着巨大的复杂性而来的是巨大的困惑。
So with great complexity comes great confusion.
这就是为什么我是极简主义者，我想在所有情况下找到最简单的解决方案
So that's why I'm minimalist, I want to find the simplest solution in all cases
因为这些都是最容易推理的事情。
because those are the things that are easiest to reason about.
所以我们应该让一切都尽可能的简单。
So we should keep everything as simple as we can.
我们应该尽可能保持我们的代码库干净。
We should keep our code bases as clean as we can.
如果我们允许我们的代码库变得粗糙，那么它们就会变得更难理解
If we allow our code bases to get crufty then they become harder to understand more
很可能会令人困惑，并且会被利用。
likely to be confusing and will get exploited.
所以我们应该总是编写好代码。
So we should always code well.
好的代码最终比坏的代码更便宜。
Good code is ultimately cheaper to produce than bad code.
所以我们应该总是写出好的代码。
So we should always make good code.
好的代码更容易推理。
Good code is easier to reason about.
难以推理的代码更有可能是有问题的，并且
Code that is difficult to reason about is more likely to be problematic and
我们应该严格遵守好的作风规则。
we should have strict conformance to good style rules.
这意味着如果我们用JavaScript编写
Which means that if we're writing in JavaScript
所有内容都应该无一例外地通过JSLint。
everything should pass JSLint without exceptions.
我们不应该在网络上发布任何至少不那么好的东西。
We should not put anything out on the web which is not at least that good.
你永远不应该相信一台不在你绝对控制之下的机器
You should never trust a machine that is not under your absolute control and
那么我甚至不能确定这些都是不是真的。
then I'm not even sure about all of those.
但有一件事是肯定的，你永远不能相信浏览器。
But one thing for sure, you must never trust the browser.
它不能也不会保护你的利益。
It cannot and will not protect your interests.
您需要正确过滤和验证从浏览器获得的所有输入，
You need to properly filter and validate all inputs that you get from the browser,
需要对发送到浏览器的所有内容进行正确编码，
need to properly encode everything that you send to the browser,
编码和解码和过滤的上下文是关键的。
the context of that encoding and decoding and filtering is critical.
您需要针对正确的上下文进行过滤和编码。
You need to filter and code for the correct context.
所以让我告诉你我关于信任浏览器的意思。
So let me tell you what I mean about trusting the browser.
所以这是一个真实的故事，几年前，
So this is a true story, a few years ago,
我的一个朋友打算去访问中国。
a friend of mine was going to go visit China.
所以他在一家著名的航空公司买了一张机票
So he bought a ticket on a famous airline and
这是一个昂贵的航班，所以他买了一张二等舱的票。
it's an expensive flight so he bought a coach ticket.
然后，他意识到，哇，这真的是一次很长的飞行，真的很不舒服，
And then, he realized, wow, it's a really long flight, it's really uncomfortable,
升级到头等舱要好得多。
it be much nicer to upgrade to first class.
所以，他去了航空公司的网站，然后
And so, he went to the website of the airline, and
查看是否有升级可用。
look to see if upgrades were available.
它们确实是，但您需要一定数量的升级证书，并且
And they were, but you needed a certain number of upgrade certificates, and
它告诉他的号码是零，因为他不经常坐飞机。
it told him his number was zero, because he doesn't fly all that often.
所以他非常失望，直到他打开调试器。
So he was very disappointed until he opened the debugger.
&gt；&gt；扬声器2：[laugh]&gt；&gt；Douglas：他发现了变量
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: [LAUGH] &gt;&gt; Douglas: He found the variable that
包含了他的一些证书。
contained his number of certificates.
他坐头等舱去了中国。
And he flew first class to China.
&gt；&gt；道格拉斯：这是一个真实的故事。
&gt;&gt; Douglas: It's a true story.
&gt；&gt；Douglas：成功的原因是，设计这个系统的人假设
&gt;&gt; Douglas: The reason that worked was, the guys who designed that system assumed
只有一组特定的URL才能生成特定的URL
that there is a certain URL that could only be generated if a certain set of
条件是真的，他们依赖浏览器来保证这一点。
conditions were true, and they were relying on the browser to guarantee that.
而且浏览器不会保证这一点，您不能信任浏览器。
And the browser will not guarantee that, you cannot trust the browser.
另一个浏览器故事。
Another browser story.
在作为电子商务的最初几天，当在线商店开始出现时，
In the first days as an e-commerce when online stores first started happening,
他们还不知道如何扩展网络系统。
they didn't understand yet how to scale web systems.
好吧。他们试图做
Right. They tried to do
一台服务器中的所有工作以及非常快速的数据，
all of the work in one server and very quickly the data,
而且交通流量超过了一个箱子所能处理的范围，他们非常恐慌。
and amount of traffic was bigger than one box could handle, and they were panic.
差不多在同一时间，JavaScript上线了，他们走了，太好了，
About the same time JavaScript comes online and they go, great,
我们现在可以将所有这些处理卸载到浏览器上。
we can now offload all this processing onto the browser.
所以他们现在让浏览器做准备发票的所有工作
So they now have the browser do all the work of preparing the invoice and
全部都准备好了。
totalling everything up.
他们只是允许浏览器提交这个东西，然后发送出去
They just allow the browser to then submit this thing which then gets sent
直接实现。
directly to fulfillment.
&gt；&gt；Douglas：所以如果你能知道如何输入URL，
&gt;&gt; Douglas: So if you can figure out how to type a URL,
你可以订购任何你想要的东西，并支付你认为合理的任何东西。
you can order anything you want and pay whatever you think is reasonable.
&gt；&gt；扬声器2：[laugh]&gt；&gt；Douglas：SO
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: [LAUGH] &gt;&gt; Douglas: So
事实证明，在浏览器中做事情是有很好的理由的，
it turns out there are good reasons to do stuff in the browser,
它们中的大多数都是为了提供更好的用户体验。
most of them are to provide a better user experience.
因此您可以避免用户填写表单并
So you can avoid the thing where the user fills in a form and
然后你把它踢回他们的牙齿，因为他们做错了什么，
then you kick it back in their teeth because they got something wrong,
我们可以帮助他们做到这一点，并使之令人愉快。
we can help them do that and make it pleasant.
但这并不意味着服务器不应该检查它的每个细节
But that doesn't mean that the server shouldn't check every detail of it and
确保它的发生是正确的，你必须这样做。
make sure that it happened right, you have to do that.
所以模板就是这个过程，今天下午我们将更多地讨论模板，
So templating is this process, we'll talk more about templating this afternoon,
我讨厌模板，因为浏览器是指着你脑袋的枪
I hate templating, because the browser is a gun pointed at your head and
模板是扣动扳机的。
templating is what pulls the trigger.